historytoday.com 2019-06-30

# Privacy Policy | History Today

Your personal information is being processed by History Today Ltd (“we”). We are committed to managing your personal information in accordance with current legislation and best practice. Our aim is to be responsible, relevant and secure when using your data. You can find out more about us by visiting [www.historytoday.com/about-us](https://www.historytoday.com/about-us).

Whenever you provide personal information we will treat that information in accordance with this Notice. We endeavour at all times to keep your data accurate and secure, and to honour your data preferences with regard to receipt of direct marketing e.g. email, mobile messaging and mobile telephone calls.

History Today Ltd publishes History Today magazine, the website [www.historytoday.com](http://www.historytoday.com/) and the History Today app for Apple, Android and Kindle Fire, all of which are governed by this Privacy Notice. 

### **What information we collect**

To provide you with the best possible customer experience we may ask you to submit personal information such as your name, postcode, email address and mobile phone number. Providing this personal information helps us to provide you with a better experience e.g. not having to login to websites each time you visit and showing you content that really interests you.

Additionally we use web technologies e.g. cookies and web beacons, to automatically track and log limited personal data and link this with information you or other suppliers have provided. See our [cookies policy](https://www.historytoday.com/cookies-policy) for more. For detailed information on Cookies and how you can choose to allow or prevent sites accessing cookies, see [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

Anonymous data will be recorded for the purpose of reporting web traffic statistics, advertisement 'click-throughs', and/or other activities on our sites.

History Today Ltd may sometimes use cookie technology to help improve its digital marketing campaigns and improve user experience across its products. This technology allows History Today Ltd to target relevant adverts to you across a number of other websites that share the same advertising technology platforms. Third party vendors including partners like Google serve advertising across the Internet based on cookies which are left on your device when you visit a website. These cookies help target relevant advertising to our users based on previous visits and behaviour. You can opt out of Google’s use of cookies by visiting Google’s Ads Settings or you can opt out of additional third-party vendor cookies by visiting the Network Advertising Initiative opt out page.

Our iPad, Android and other apps may collect user data which we use to learn about our readers and improve the app. 

### **How we use your data**

The personal information we obtain will be used for the following purposes.

We may use third party suppliers to provide part of our service to you. In some circumstances these providers may be based in countries outside the European Economic Area whose laws provide for a different standard of protection for your personal information than that provided under UK Law. In such circumstances we will have in place strict contractual arrangements that will require your information is processed securely, at least to a standard equivalent to the UK Data Protection Act 1998.

Your personal data will not be disclosed to state institutions and authorities except if required by law or other regulation. Before we release data on this basis, we will ensure that the information is being provided to a genuine and properly authorised investigation. If we are not satisfied that there are valid grounds for releasing the information, the Data Protection Act does not oblige us to do so. If we refuse to release the information, law enforcement agencies may obtain a court order requiring us to provide it.

### **Access to Personal Information**

If you wish, you can obtain a copy of any personal information we have about you by sending your request to The Data Controller, History Today Ltd, 2nd Floor, 9 Staple Inn, London WC1V 9DT, United Kingdom. We will provide you, at no charge, with a hard copy of the personal data that we keep about you within 30 days, although we will require proof of your identity. If you consider that the information we hold about you is incorrect, you may where appropriate, have the data erased, amended or updated.

### **Personal information security**

History Today Ltd security policies, rules and technical measures have been implemented to protect your personal information from unauthorised or improper use and from accidental loss.

All our employees and data processors that have access to, and are associated with, the processing of your personal information are legally obliged to respect the confidentiality of your data and are bound by contract to do so.

Note that some of our websites provide forums where you can post information. When you do so, be aware that other visitors may collect any information you make public.

### **Privacy Support**

If you have an enquiry or concern about our Privacy Notice, please contact: The Data Controller, History Today Ltd, 2nd Floor, 9 Staple Inn, London WC1V 9DT, United Kingdom. If you are not satisfied with our response you may wish to contact the Information Commissioner via their website

If we decide to change our Privacy Notice we will post these changes on this page so that you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it and in what circumstances we disclose it.

In the event of any part of History Today Ltd either being sold or going into receivership, we reserve the right to continue to share your data to third parties in accordance with the latest preferences you have provided. You will be informed should any change of ownership occur, and the new owner will manage your personal information preferences.
